for some reason the moon is one size larger tonight
konya no tsuki wa nazeka hitomawari ookikute
it's shining brighter than it usually does
itsumo yori akaruku terasu
I trudge along the road home with my shoulders hunched
senaka wo marumete tobotobo kaeru michi
at any time I will always have a friend
donna toki mo mikata wa iru
without saying a word, it's all right to cry
nani mo iwazu naketara ii ne
once my tears dry, it will all be over
namida ga karetara owari
I need to become stronger...
motto boku ga tsuyoku naranakya
sorrow is the first step towards independence
kanashimi wa jiritsu he no ippo
how many times do I have to get hurt to forget the pain?
nando kizutsukeba itami wo wasureru
when I bleed red, I'm reminded of life
akai chi wo nagaseba inochi wo omoidasu sa
I collapse on the road with my arms and legs spread out
michi ni taore dainoji ni
I look up at the sky and think
sora wo miagete omou
true loneliness is someone without a past
shin no kodoku to wa kako no nai mono
someone who only knows the present
ima shika shiranu mono
I'm in Hell
Hey there.
（ゼツ）やあ。
How are you doing?
ご機嫌いかが？
Bad... What do you think?
（オビト）いいわけ　ねえだろ。
How long have I been here?
ここへ来て　どのくらい経つんだ？
It feels like it's been a while.
もうずいぶんいる気がする。
Don't worry,
you don't need to pay rent.
家賃いらないから　心配ないよ。
Those of us created from
the Gedo Statue don't have to eat either.
魔像から作られた僕らは
食事しなくてもいいしね。
No food bills,
no need for a bathroom.
食費もなし　トイレもなし
うんこもしないし。
We don't even poo!
Don't lump me in with you guys!
だからって
お前らと俺を一緒にするなよ。
I just have half of that weird stuff
stuck onto me.
俺は半分　その訳わかんないのが
くっついてるだけだ。
And thanks to that, you can survive
without eating or drinking.
そのおかげで　キミも飲まず食わずで
生きてられるんだよ。
In fact, you should be grateful
and thank us.
逆に　ありがとうって
感謝してほしいくらいだよ。
Good grief. We're the ones who don't want
to be lumped in with you!
まったく　こっちこそ
一緒にされたくないね。
What you have is
emotionless synth-tissue.
キミのは感情のない人造体。
We are full artificial humans.
We have feelings and everything!
僕らは人造人間。
ちゃんと感情がある。
You may have a better sense of humor,
but what we have is much better!
それも　ちゃんと笑いのわかる
キミよりいいのがね。
Both our vocabulary skills and mental acuity
are far higher than yours!
ボキャブラリーも頭のキレも
キミより上っすよ。
But we don't poo...
うんこはしないけど。
Shut up!
うるせぇ！
All right, explain how you're at
a higher level than I am!
なら　お前らが俺よりレベル上だって
説明してみろよ。
僕らが。
キミを。
We are...
The ones...
– in charge of watching you!
（２人）見張ってる。
Don't talk in synch!
That pisses me off!
声揃えてんじゃねえ！　むかつく！
We're only helping you
with your rehab
リハビリを手伝ってるのは→
because Madara ordered us
to get you up and running
マダラが起きるまでに
キミを回復させて→
and usable by the time he wakes up.
使えるようにって
命令されてるからだし。
ケッ！　こんな口先だけの
デク人形どもに見張らせて→
So he makes these noisy puppets
keep an eye on me...
while he gets to sleep
the whole time?
自分はずっとおねむかよ。
I swear I'm gonna get outta here
and return to Rin and Kakashi!
ぜってぇ　こんなとこ抜け出して
リンとカカシに会うんだ。
Where's the exit?
どこから出られる？
Can't be done... there's no exit.
無理無理！　出口ないよ。
Madara sealed it off
with a huge boulder...
マダラの命令で
キミをここへ運んだあと→
after we lugged you here
on his orders.
でっかい岩でフタされちゃったから。
What?! He sealed us in?!
（オビト）おい！　塞いだのかよ！
By the way, you've been saying
"Rin-Rin-Rin" in your sleep a lot.
そもそも　前からずっと
リンリンリン　寝言いってますけど→
Do you want to go outside to
collect a bell or something?
外に鈴でも
拾いにいきたいんすか？
Once in a while,
you said "stupid-stupid-stupid.”
たまに　バカバカ　バカバカ！　って。
And "stupid Kakashi."
あっ　バカカシとも言うよね？
Yeah, yeah, that's right!
Every so often.
ああ　そうそう　たま～にね。
What's a "stupid Kakashi"?
バカカシって何？
さあ　直接聞いてみたら？
Beats me. Why don't you ask him?
Was I really saying that?
《んなこと言ってんのか　俺…》
（２人）ヒソヒソ　ヒソヒソヒソ…。
Um, may we ask you a question!
あの　ちょっと質問いいですか？
（オビト）あっ！？
What?
When nature calls...
便意…　つまり
うんこをしたくなる気持って→
In short, what does the urge
to poo feel like?
どんな感じ？　たとえて。
For example...
I thought you wanted to know
about stupid Kakashi!
バカカシじゃねえのかよ！？
Why are you guys so obsessed
with poop?
うんこに　どんだけ興味あんだ
お前ら！
You don't have to get so angry.
何もそんなに怒んなくても。
All right, we'll ask you about
Rin and stupid Kakashi later.
じゃあ
あとでリンとバカカシについて聞くよ。
Especially you, with the swirly face...
特にそっちのグルグル！
You don't poop,
but you look like poop.
うんこしねえくせに
うんこみてぇなヤツな。
I hate you!
お前は嫌！
Anyway, where'd the other white guys go?
それより　他の白いのどこ行った？
They went outside to collect intel.
えっと　外行って情報収集。
What?! You guys can get out?
えっ！？
外へ出られんのかよ？　お前ら。
We can all move through
the earth's surface.
僕ら
地面の中を移動できるからね。
はぁ…　なんだよ　それ。
What the hell?!
I'm locked up in here,
俺はこんなとこに閉じ込められ
訳わかんねえ話をされ…。
and I have to hear about all
this weird stuff.
So sorry to have bothered you
about poo!
うんこの話して　すんませんっす！
That's not what I meant!
その話じゃねえよ！
I mean, what Madara talked about!
マダラの話したほう。
Something about severing fate
and all...
インガを切るだのなんだのと…。
Oh, that...
ああ　ガキに合わせて話すほど
人間できてないから。　マダラ。
Madara's not nice enough to talk
to a brat at his level.
Simply put, he's talking
about discarding
まあ　簡単に言うとね→
all the bad things in the real world and
本当の世の中の　イヤなことを捨て→
escaping inside a dream
that's full of good things!
いいことだらけの夢の中に
逃げちゃおうって話。
Inside a dream?
夢の中？
夢だから→
Since it's a dream,
everything is how you want it!
なんだって思いどおり。
Even those who are dead
can be alive again!
死んだ人だって
生きてることにできる。
ん　ああ…　幻術で
で～っかい夢の世界つくって→
Yeah...
Just think of it as all of us going
to this huge dream world
that was created using genjutsu!
そこに　みんなで行こうってこと。
Well, it's more like forcibly
taking everyone there...
行こうっていうよりは　無理やり
連れてく感じなんだけど。
and for life too.
しかも　一生ね。
With genjutsu?
幻術で？
はぁ…　今度はバカバカしすぎて
意味わかんねえよ！
That's so beyond stupid,
I can't even understand it.
マダラくらい力があれば
なんだってできるよ。
If you have as much power as Madara,
anything is possible.
It's just that he's weak right now
and can't do it yet.
ただ　今は　弱っててできないよ。
Much still needs to be prepared.
だから
いろいろと準備があんのさ。
Oh really? Well, I'm not interested.
あっそう。
興味ねえな。
More importantly...
ん～なことより
俺は　ぜってぇ外へ出るからな！
I swear I'm gonna make it outside!
And get back to Rin and Kakashi!
リンとカカシのもとに。
What?
なに？
この体　使えるようにしねえと。
I've got to get this body working again...
んっ　ああ！
ばんざ～い！
Yaaaay!
ハハハ！
げっ！
What?!
なっ！？
Don't act tough and hide your wounds!
((強がって傷を隠してもダメ。
(ちゃんと見てんだから))
I'm always watching, you know.
《なじんできてる。
It's starting to feel natural.
もう少し…　もう少しで会えるぞ
リン　カカシ》
Just a bit longer.
I'll see you soon, Rin... Kakashi!
I was just outside!
さっき　外行ってたんだけど→
Your friends, Rin and
stupid Kakashi, are in trouble!
キミの言ってた　リンとバカカシってのが
やばいよ。
What happened?!
何があった？
They're alone and completely
surrounded by Hidden Mist Shinobi!
２人きりで　霧隠れの忍たちに
囲まれてる。
うっ　ああ…。
く…。
You can't break through boulders
with that body yet.
まだ　その体じゃ
岩は壊せやしないよ。
I have to save Rin and Kakashi...
リンと　カカシを助けに行かなきゃ。
Why don't you wear my body?
僕の体を着るといいよ。
But you guys serve Madara.
Are you sure about this?
お前ら　マダラの部下だろ。
いいのか？
その子は　いい子だ。
He's... a good boy.
（ゼツ）リンとカカシを
助けたいんでしょ？
Don't you want to help
Rin and Kakashi?
ありがとう　お前ら。
Thanks, you guys!
You kept the root tethered and
borrowed the statue's power eh? Nice.
根をつなげたまま
魔像の力を借りたのね。
やるじゃん。
I'm pretty good, huh?
（ゼツ）僕って　やるもんでしょ。
All right!
よし！
So you're going?
（マダラ）行くか。
I'm grateful that you saved me.
助けてくれたことには感謝する。
But I'm leaving. I have to go.
けど　俺は行く
行かなきゃならねえから。
You're being too hasty...
お前は焦りすぎる。
It may be premature to thank me.
感謝は　まだ早いかもしれんぞ。
I'll probably never come back here.
たぶん　ここへは二度と来ねえ。
I've given my thanks.
一応　礼は言った。　もう行く。
I'm going!
You... will return.
お前は　ここへ帰ってくる。
And that's when I'll get
your true gratitude.
そのときこそ
本当の礼をもらおう。
白いの！
リンとカカシの場所はどこだ？
White one!
What's Rin and Kakashi's location?!
Take me there right away!
今すぐ案内してくれ。
What you've got on your body
is like a clone of me.
キミの体についたのは
いわば　僕の分身。
And we can talk telepathically to
each other over limited distances.
僕らは　ある程度の距離なら
テレパシーで会話できるし→
Others of us are scattered
here and there underground.
他の分身体も
あちこちの地下に点在してて→
We're able to exchange intel.
情報をやり取りしてる。
I'll use them to guide you.
それを使って　キミを誘導するよ。
グルグル…。
Swirly!
First, we need to get outside.
まずは外へ。
頼む。
I'm counting on you.
How are Rin and Kakashi
doing right now?
今のリンとカカシの状況は？
According to the others,
it looks pretty bad.
仲間からの情報だと
かなり　やばいみたいだよ。
They're talking about some
Hidden Mist test subjects,
霧隠れの実験体が
どうこうとか言ってるけど→
but I don't really understand.
僕は　よくわかんない。
Test subjects?
実験体？
Anyway, it seems Rin and Kakashi
are totally surrounded.
とにかく　リンもカカシも
数十人に囲まれてるみたい。
And they're saying they all appear
to be jonin or Black Ops.
それも　みんな凄腕の上忍や
暗部みたいのばっかだって。
What's Minato Sensei doing?
ミナト先生は何してる？
誰？
Who is that?
I'm asking you what the Yellow Flash
of the Leaf is doing!
黄色い閃光は何してる
って聞いてんだ。
う～ん…
何か別の任務中みたいだね。
Seems he's on a different mission.
At a time like this?!
こんなときに…。
Kakashi... Look after Rin for me.
((カカシ　リンを頼むぜ。
I will.
(（カカシ）あぁ))
Kakashi! You made me a promise!
《オビト：カカシ　お前は約束してくれた。
Please...
リンを…。
リンをなんとか守ってくれ！》
Please protect Rin somehow!
I'll be right there!
俺も　もうすぐ駆けつける。
Obito, this will probably turn
into a battle.
オビト　たぶん　これから戦闘になる。
So I want to tell you
some things beforehand.
その前に少し
言っときたいんだけど。
What is it?!
Your fighting ability is lower
than mine.
何だ？
キミの戦闘能力は僕より低い。
Plus right now, it's like my big body
is wrapped around
更に今は
キミの傷ついた小さな体に→
and protecting
your wounded little body.
大きな僕の体が覆って
保護してるって感じだから…。
So what?!
だから何だよ！？
I think it would be better
if I do all the fighting.
戦闘は僕が動いたほうが
いいと思うけど。
Remember what Madara said?
マダラも言ってただろ。
That only with a pair together
写輪眼は　左右揃って
本来の力を発揮するって。
can the Sharingan's true power
be unleashed!
Kakashi, the other half of my pair,
will be on the battlefield.
戦場には
俺と対になる写輪眼のカカシがいる。
Our combo attacks are superior!
ヤツとのコンビネーションは　俺のが上だ！
Kakashi and I will protect Rin!
俺とカカシで　リンを守る！
As I recall, you do have
Hashirama's tissue attached to you.
確かにキミには
柱間の人造体がくっついてる。
A whole different strength may emerge
千手とうちは
両方の力が合わされば→
when Senju and Uchiha powers
are combined together, but...
今までとは違う強さが
あらわれるかもしれないけど…。
What was that?
何だ？
I thought it was rain, but it's...
雨かと思ったら　あれか。
I just got word from one of my guys.
仲間から連絡あり。
It seems...
どうやら　あそこみたいだね。
That's the location.
Let's go!
行くぞ！
What's happening?!
《何だ　これ。
Stop showing these weird images!
変なイメージしてんじゃねえ！
A little bit...
もう少し…　もう少しだ！》
Just a little bit farther!
Kakashi...
カカシ…。
Damn it! He did it!
クソッ　やられた！
After all the trouble
we went through to get her!
せっかく苦労して
手に入れたものを！
Rin...
リン…。
うお～っ！
Where...
《ここは　いったい　ここは何だ》
in the world...
is this place?!
Who is that guy?
ヤツは何だ？
増援か？
Reinforcements maybe?
What a fool, jumping in alone!
バカが！　たった１人で！
I won't accept it!
《認めるか！》
I will not...
《こんなもの！》
What just happened?!
何だ　今のは！？
かわしたのか！？
Did he dodge them?
... accept any of this!
《認めてやるもんか！》
Do not mock the Blood Mist Village!
血霧の里をなめるなよ！
Die!
《死ね！》
ぐあ～っ！
I can't hit him!
当たらない！？
Who is that guy?!
何だ　アイツは！？
奇妙な術を使う！
He wields a strange jutsu!
At least grab the girl!
せめて女だけでも回収しろ！
死体を絶対　敵に渡すな！
Don't hand her corpse over
to the enemy!
There's no mistake!
This guy passes right through you!
コイツ　間違いない！
すり抜けやがる！
All of a sudden,
（ゼツ）木遁　挿し木の術をいきなり！
he's able to use
the Wood Style Cutting Sprigs Jutsu...
Obito, now I understand
why Madara chose you!
オビト…　キミが　マダラに選ばれた
理由がわかったよ。
うお～っ！
What is he?
何だ　アイツは？
I get it...
そうか　俺は…。
I'm...
俺は…　地獄にいる。
in Hell.
I already know
it doesn't belong to anyone else
I'll follow all the rainbows in the sky
now matter how much time passes I can never reach it
I keep repeating the same thing every day
I'm chasing a future I once dreamed of
and I was blaming it all on someone else
I already know
that I can't go on like this
can I even believe in the "future self" I saw with my own eyes anymore?
I already know
that I have to go
beyond the rainbow there's another future waiting for me
I shall sever the nexuses of this world.
That's why I came back.
So you still felt loyalty to
your one-time teammate?
No, it doesn't matter to me anymore
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
whether he's alive or
dead in this world.
美空ひばりです。
Kakashi will exist
in the world we'll create. Rin too.
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"World of Dreams"
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！にっぽんの歌』。
Teach me how to create
this world of dreams.
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手
１２組の皆さんによる→